Ahmed Ibrahim

Cairo, Egypt

ahmedibrahimhassan654@gmail.com

002 01065619208

linkedin.com/in/ahmed-ibrahim5588

Summary

I am a Technical Support Engineer at AVIT - Aviation Information Technology, where I provide solutions to software and hardware issues for clients in the aviation industry. With 7+ years of experience in this role, I have developed strong skills in diagnosing and troubleshooting technical problems, communicating effectively with customers, and working collaboratively with my team.

I am also a React JS Developer with 3+ years of experience in building responsive and user-friendly web applications using the MERN Stack, Progressive Web Apps, and GraphQL. I have completed multiple online courses and certifications to enhance my knowledge and skills in this domain. I am passionate about front-end excellence and performance optimization, and I constantly seek new challenges and opportunities to learn and grow as a developer. You can check my portfolio and projects at https://ahmedwebdev.netlify.app/.

Experience

Technical Support Engineer

AVIT - Aviation Information Technology

Jan 2017 - Present (7 years 3 months)

- -Research and identify solutions to software and hardware issues
- -Diagnose and troubleshoot technical issues, including account setup and network configuration
- -Ask customers targeted questions to quickly understand the root of the problem
- -Track computer system issues through to resolution, within agreed time limits Talk clients through a series of actions, either via phone, email or chat, until they've solved a technical issue

React Js Developer

Cam4sell

Feb 2023 - Nov 2023 (10 months)

Developed responsive pages for AppTo Rent and Booking's Products, services, and Blog using React.is, Next.is, and Material-UI for the front end.

Actively participated in Agile development processes, contributing, and daily stand-ups to enhance team efficiency

managed app state with the redux toolkit

implement strip for payment

managed the application routing with backend build with express JS and Mongo DB

Senior Software Engineer

PanExcel

Feb 2019 - Apr 2020 (1 year 3 months)

I'm working on the front end side using react with next js and material UI for user interface

Node js back end developer

Ekhliil

Dec 2021 - Feb 2022 (3 months)

building Rest API for mobile application using node Js , express Js &Mongo dB and document API with swagger

mern stack web developer

TTL EGYPT DIGITAL SOLUTIONS

Aug 2021 - Oct 2021 (3 months)

I designed and implement API endpoints for Admin DashBoard using React Js for the application called the online doctor and help CEO to implement new features for the application cooperate with node is back end developer

🌄 Satellite Network engineer

Egyptsat Telecom 2012 - 2017 (5 years)

Responsible for designing programs for orbiting satellites. Ensures satellites are functioning properly,

creates command systems, and remotely controls satellite activities.

Education

El Shorouk Academy

Bachelor's degree, Electronics and Communication Engineering 2007 - 2012

Five years college program that focus on the conceptualization, design, and development of electronic, computer and communication products, systems, services and processes.

Sero To Mastery Academy

React JS Dev May 2022 - Present

Code With Mosh

Online course, React Js Dev Jan 2022 - Present

Academind

React JS + Node Js udemy cources , Computer Software Engineering Feb 2021 - Feb 2023

Licenses & Certifications

in Learning REST APIs - LinkedIn

Node.js, Express, MongoDB & More: The Complete Bootcamp 2020 - Udemy

https://www.udemy.com/course/nodejs-express-mongodb-bootcamp/

- Master the Coding Interview: Data Structures + Algorithms Udemy https://www.udemy.com/course/master-the-coding-interview-data-structures-algorit
- Cisco Certified Network Associate Industrial (CCNA I) Cisco Issued May 2015 Expires May 2018
- in Learning MongoDB LinkedIn
- in Building RESTful APIs with Node.js and Express LinkedIn

Skills

Problem Solving • Web Technologies • Attention to Detail • Progressive Web Applications (PWAs) • Redux Thunk • redux toolkit • TypeScript • Interpersonal Skills • Troubleshooting • Technical Support